SEAN JIN

Palisades Park, NJ 07650 | 2015801534 | seanj@andrew.cmu.edu

https://github.com/seanjincmu/myprojects https://www.linkedin.com/in/sean-d-jin/ https://seandjin.com/

Education

Bachelor of Science: Statistics & Machine Learning, Cognitive Science

Expected in Dec 2020

Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

GPA: 3.24

Machine Learning (10-701); Reinforcement Learning (10-703); Advanced Algorithms (15-351); Data Structure (15-122); Learning in Humans and Machine (85-426); Research & Methods (85-310); Language and Thought (85-421); Probability (36-217); Statistical Graphics (36-315); Statistical Computing (36-350); Advance Data Analysis (36-402);

Summary

Competitive powerlifter and lifelong athlete using statistics and machine learning to support training and thought process behind strategies for different sports. Worked with a local collegiate team to a national team for AI and statistical development to support their needs for strategy and media development.

Experience

Al Integrations & Development Intern

Jun 2020 - Aug 2020

Cortex-Vertical Inc

Englewood Cliffs, NJ

- Initiated development for custom model integration for \$3.15B+ Media Management Company with 50%+ accuracy
- Developed roadmap to outline 6 sprints with 3 engineers to develop POC for partnership with Monster Energy
- Pushed for partnership with Monster Energy for collaboration in resources for model development and integration into Open Text Media Management

Sports Capstone Jan 2020 - May 2020

Carnegie Mellon Softball Team

Pittsburgh, PA

- Developed web application that displays prediction of plays for 400+ different NCAA Division 3 Softball Teams
- Created moneyball-esq application where each NCAA Division 3 Softball Team to predict actions of the opposing team
- Worked with Carnegie Mellon Softball Coaches to reinforce the decisions made for a play with statistical evidence

Gotta Graph Them All Oct 2019 - Dec 2020

Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

- Implemented PCA to differentiate types of Legendary & non-Legendary Pokémon based on stats using kernlab
- Produced graphics that display different attributes of these Pokémon Kaggle using ggplot and combining it into a poster

Estimated Taxi Travel Time Oct 2019 - Dec 2019

Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

- Extracted new features based on Taxi-Zone location within New York City in order to deal with underfitting
- Reduced RMSE by 99% from simple linear regression to XGBoost in prediction to show improvement of the models

Data Science/Full Stack Intern

Jun 2019 - Sep 2019

CertAInBuild

Remote

- Developed several UML diagrams that illustrate the structure of the web application that displays building costs of buildings
- Integrated Google Maps API to display the locations of the buildings as well as their projected price for construction
- Utilized Flask as the structure of the website where each user sees the building costs of their corresponding organization

Affiliations

Central Church – Discipleship Group Leader (Aug 2019 – May 2020) CMU Powerlifting – Founder; President (Jan 2019 – Apr 2020); State Champion (Mar 2019) Lunar Gala – Model (Oct 2019 – Feb 2020)